체스터스 밀은
평범한 마을이었다
Chester's Mill is
a place like any other.
정체불명의 돔이 나타나
At least it used to be
세상과 단절되기 전까지는
until we were cut off
from the rest of the world
적어도 그랬었다
by a mysterious dome.
보이지도 않고,
파괴할 수도 없고
Invisible, indestructible,
탈출할 수도 없었다
and completely inescapable.
우린 갇힌거야
We're trapped.
그게 어디에서 온건지,
왜 여기에 생긴건지
We don't know where it
came from or why it's here,
알 수는 없지만,
우리는 돔 안에 갇혔고
but now that we're all trapped
under the dome together,
마을의 비밀은
더 이상 숨길 수 없게 됐다
none of our secrets are safe.
분홍별이야
It's the pink stars.
분홍별들이
별자리를 만들고 있어
And they're making constellations.
그게 무슨 뜻이에요?
What does it mean?
남편은 당신이 자신을
Peter got in over his head
죽여주길 원했어요
and forced you to kill
him to defend himself.
오늘 이 생명 보험증권을
찾았어요
I found this life insurance policy...
자살을 하면,
법적 효력이 없기 때문이죠
This would be void if he committed suicide.
- 안녕, 맥스
- 지난 며칠간 쭉 널 지켜봤어
- Hello, Max.
- The past few days I've been watching you.
나한테 무슨 일이라도 생기면,
당신들의 비밀은 폭로될거야
Anything bad happens to me,
your secret's gonna come out.
내 딸 맥신이지
That's my daughter, Maxine.
자 이제 등 뒤에 있는
총 빼놓고...
Now do me a favour and
drop that gun that...
아가사!!
Annabelle!
살려줘!
Please!
멋지다
It's amazing.
It's still just a barn, Galileo.
알에 있는 모든 점들이 투영됐어
그런데 이게 무슨 뜻일까?
Great, so we painted dots over those lights
from the egg. What does that mean?
돔이 소통을
원하는게 아닐까?
Maybe the dome is trying to communicate.
비가 오게 해서
폭동도 멈춰주고,
It stopped the riots with rain,
분홍별에 대해서
수다도 떨게 해주고...
made us babble about pink stars...
우리한테 뭔가
할 말이 있는거 같아
I wonder what it's trying to tell us now.
모르겠다
I don't know.
이 별 네개는
투영된 게 아니야
These four stars aren't
part of any constellation.
우릴 가리키는 거 같아
I think they're us.
이 번데기는 도대체
뭐하는 놈일까?
What's this guy have to do with that?
밤새 색깔이 변했어
It changed color over night.
녹색이었다가 투명해졌네
날개가 돋으려고 하나
From green to clear. I see its wings now.
제왕나비야, 알을 깨고 나와서
나비가 될걸 진짜 멋진데
It's a monarch. It's gonna hatch
into a butterfly. It's pretty rad.
멋지기는 개뿔!
개소리야
It's not rad. It's insane.
우리가 무슨 우주 미스테리의
수호자라도 된다고?
We're like the guardians of
some secret cosmic mystery.
말도 안돼,
오바야
It's too much, it's too much.
다른 사람들한테
얘기해야 돼
We gotta tell somebody.
돔은 다른 사람한테
The dome's been pretty clear
알려지기를 원치
않는 거 같은데
about not wanting anyone else
to know about it.
도디도 몰래 숨어 들었다가
When Dodee snuck in here,
감전돼서 병원에
실려 갔잖아
she got zapped
and wound up in the hospital.
줄리아 아줌마는
괜찮겠지
We could tell Julia.
아줌마가 이거
만졌을 때는, 내 환영이
When she touched this thing,
『The monarch will be crowned.』
라고 말해줬다고
she said my ghost told her that
the monarch will be crowned.
아줌마가 우리 일원은
아니더라도
Maybe she's not one of us,
뭔가 해답을
갖고 계실거야
but she might have some answers.
조 말이 맞아
JUNIOR:
He's right.
저게 알을 까고 나오면
That thing's gonna hatch,
그 때가 되면,
and when it does,
저게.. 우리를 어딘가로
이끌지 몰라
maybe it will...
lead us to something.
그게 사람일 수도 있고
Or someone.
제왕이 의미하는 사람
같은거
Like the monarch's a person.
왕 같은 사람
말야
Like a king maybe.
그게 누구든,
돔이 사라지게 해주겠지
Who might be able
to bring the dome down.
좋아
All right.
결론은 돔이
줄리아 아줌마는 믿는거네
So the dome trusts Julia.
조, 가서 말씀드려
Joe, go tell her.
의원님이 저와 의견이 같은지
확인만 하면 됩니다
I just want to make sure
that we're on the same page.
그러니까 의원님은,
서장님하고 코긴스 목사가
So, you, Duke Perkins and
Reverend Coggins conspired
막대한 양의 프로판을 얻으려고
음모를 꾸몄다는 말씀이세요?
to acquire a vast
amount of propane?
그래, 프로판을 구매하고,
장부에서 삭제했다니까
Yeah, we bought propane
off the books.
마을이 도산을 면하려면
어쩔수 없었어
But only to keep
this town afloat.
그걸 맥신 시그레이브 씨한테
팔아서요?
By selling it to
Maxine Seagrave?
마약상한테?
A drug dealer?
그런데 그걸 의원님은 창고에
계속 보관해 오셨잖아요
But you kept some of
it in your warehouse.
그렇게 한걸
신께 감사드려야 할거야
And you can thank
the Lord that we did.
지금, 이 지옥같은 곳에서
Because right now
in the middle of this...
한줄기 빛이 됐잖나
nightmare, the lights are on.
자네 발전기도
Because your generator
is running
내 프로판으로
돌아가고 있는거라고
using my propane.
로즈네 식당도
내 프로판으로 다시 열었고
The diner's open
because of my propane.
작물재배랑 물물교환도
다 프로판 덕이라고
We're setting up irrigation
for crops, bartering systems.
그래서 마을이 아직
돌아가는 거라고
Hell, Chester's Mill
might just stay alive
내 프로판 가스 때문에
말이지
because of my propane.
내가 사기꾼 같아?
You think I'm a crook?
(laughs)
마을이 나한테
빚진 거라고
I think I'm owed a damn parade.
돔이 무너지지
않는다고 해도
You know, it doesn't change
달라지는 건 없어요
the fact that if this dome
hadn't come down,
의원님은
감옥행이에요
you'd be in jail.
그게 당신을
살리는 거라구요, 빅 짐
I'd say it saved
your ass, Big Jim.
그래, 어디 해보게
So, go ahead.
날 기소해서
음모를 밝혀보라고
Charge me with conspiracy
to keep the lights on.
아니면...
Or...
가서 진짜 범죄자들을
잡던지
...you can go after
a real criminal.
또 누가 죄를 저질러요
And who might that be?
이 마을에는
Someone who's a real mystery
진짜 이상한 사람이 있지
in this town.
마을에 막 온 사람
A man who just got here.
실속만 챙기는 사람
Who's only out for himself.
주민들이...
And isn't shy about...
좋아할만한 사람
letting people know it.
소파에서 자니까 어때요?
How was the couch?
외롭네요
Lonely.
침대도 그렇겠죠
So was the bed.
제가 떠났으면 좋겠어요?
Do you want me to leave?
절 피터 무덤으로
데려가 주세요
I want you to take me
to Peter's grave.
우리 관계가
진전되길 원하면,
For us to move forward,
일을 매듭져야 해요
I need closure.
당신도 마찬가지구요
I think you do, too.
그러니까...
So...
네, 피터 무덤에
가보고 싶어요
yeah, I need
to see Peter's grave.
옷 입고 올게요
I'll go get dressed.
제가 바비를 조사하길
바라시는거죠?
LINDA:
You want me to go after Barbie?
그 사람이 뭘 했길래요
What did he ever do?
정신차려, 린다
Wake up, Linda.
바비는 단순히 이 마을을
지나는 길이 아니었어
Barbie wasn't just passing
through Chester's Mill.
여기에서, 맥신 시그레이브 일을
해주고 있다고
He was here,
working for Max Seagrave.
바비가요?
He was?
맥스 도박장에서
어깨노릇을 한다고
That's her gambling enforcer.
여기 머물면서 마을을
쑥대밭으로 만들고 있어,
He was here putting the screws
to people in this town--
our town.
우리 마을을
아뇨, 그거는...
No, this sounds...
개소리라고?
지금까지는 그렇지
Crazy? Till it's true.
한동안 못 들은 이름 있잖아
Here's a name
you haven't heard in a while.
피터 셤웨이라고
Peter Shumway.
피터는 맥스한테
어마어마한 빚을 졌어
He was up to his eyeballs
in debt to Max.
바비는 돔이 생기던 날
피터랑 같이 있었고
Barbie was with him
the day the dome came down.
그래서 뭐냐고?
And guess what?
그날 이후
피터 소식 들은 거 있나?
Haven't heard a peep
from old Peter since.
사람마다 비밀들이
있다고는 하지만...
You know,
some people have secrets you...
자넨 상상도 못할거야
you couldn't imagine.
의원님은 어때요?
What about you?
난 거리낄 것 없네
I'm an open book.
(doorbell rings)
제가 갈게요
I got it.
무슨 일이시죠?
Can I help you?
이제, 당신도
어쩌진 못하겠지
Right now,
you can't even help yourself.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
UNDER THE DOME
SEASON 1 EPISODE 11
Speak of the Devil
줄리아!
Julia!
정신차려요
Hold on.
린다, 제 말 들려요?
Linda, are you there?
말씀하세요,
바비
LINDA (over radio):
I'm here, Barbie.
줄리아가 총에
맞았어요
Julia's been shot!
뭐라구요?
벨소리를 듣고 나갔는데
What?
She answered the door
- 누군가 쐈다구요
- 누가요?
and somebody shot her.
Who?
모르겠어요
I don't know!
바비를 믿나?
If you can believe him.
린다, 잘 들어요
Linda, listen, I can't drive
지혈을 해야 해서
운전을 할 수 없어요
and keep her from bleeding out
at the same time.
운전할 수 있는 사람 좀
빨리 보내줘요
I need someone
to give me a ride right now.
제가 바로 갈게요, 바비
I'll be right there, Barbie.
린다...
잘 생각해
Linda... think.
잘 생각해 봐
Think.
배고파?
You hungry?
응
Yeah.
우리 집 닭이 아직
알 낳고 있을거야
Well, our chickens
are still laying eggs.
스크렘블 좀 해줄게
I can scramble some up.
믿겨져, 앤지?
Can you believe it, Angie?
아니, 그냥...
Uh, no, it's...
모든게 좀
이상하긴 하지
all been pretty crazy.
우리 말이야
I mean us.
나...나는...
I... I, uh...
운명같은 거 진짜
믿지 않았는데
I never thought fate was real.
이거는.. 뭔가..
That there was this...
계획된 거 같아
plan.
거부할 수 없는 거 같아
But now it's undeniable.
무슨 말이야?
What are you talking about?
우리 인생이
엮여 있는거 같다고
The way our lives are
braided together.
영원히 말야
And they will be forever.
뭐? 너 미쳤어?
What? Are you insane?!
날 또 죄수 취급하려고?
You kept me prisoner, okay?
난 이미 그 지하실에서 죽었어!
I almost died down there!
근데, 죽지 않았잖아
But you didn't.
우리 둘 다 살아있고,
여기 이렇게 같이 있잖아
We're both alive
and we're here right now.
우린 네 명이
이어진거야
It is the four of us
who are connected.
너랑 나
단 둘이 아니고
It is not about you and me.
너랑은 절대 엮이...
It will never be about you...
- 난 너 안 믿어
- 그럼, 그냥 믿어!
I don't believe you.
Well, believe it!
우린 절대
함께 할 수 없어
We will never be together!
그리고 우리가 뭘 어떻게 해서
이 돔을 무너뜨리면
And if somehow
we make this dome come down,
난 떠날거야
then I am gone, too.
그리고 우린 절대
만날 일이 없을거야
And you will never see me again.
그럼, 난 그만둘래
Then I'm out.
뭐?
What?
너랑 안해, 이딴
I'm done with you, with this,
미니돔 따위,
전부 안해!
the mini-dome, all of it.
나가면 안돼
You can't just walk out.
- 우린 네 도움이...
- 내 손?
We need your...
My hand?
나도 알아
내 손이 미니돔에 필요한거
I know...
my hand on the little dome
분홍별도 만들고,
저게 원하는
so we can make pink stars and do
좆같은 것들 하는데도
필요하겠지
whatever the hell else
it wants to do.
이게 우리 유일한 해결책이야
This might be our only shot.
그런데, 침 뱉고 그냥
나가겠다고?
(chuckles) And you're gonna
ruin that out of spite?
(wind blowing)
너처럼 이기적인 새끼는
처음 본다!
I've never met someone
so selfish!
사랑이야, 앤지
It's love, Angie.
너랑 헤어지느니
I'd rather live in here
여기서 살고
여기서 죽을래
and die in here
than be apart from you.
(door slams)
(wind howling)
(engine sputtering)
씨발!
Damn it!
환장하겠구만
Great.
이젠 경찰체면에
절도도 해야겠네
Now even the cops
are getting ripped off.
좀 태워주세요!
I need a ride!
기름 없어!
No gas.
(groans)
멈춰!
Stop your vehicle!
(tires screech)
뭐여, 지금 차 뺐는거에요?
What, are you carjacking me?
필, 나 좀 줄리아한테
데려다 줘
Phil, I need a ride to Julia's.
총에 맞았데
She just got shot.
타세요
Get in.
(wind howling)
- 조!
- 바비 아저씨?
Joe!
Barbie?
야, 빨리 이리 좀 와!
Hey, get in here right now!
맙소사!
Oh, my God.
운전할 줄 아니?
Can you drive?
네, 임시 면허증이
있긴 한데
Uh, yeah. I have
my learner's permit,
연습을 더 해야 한다고...
but the guy said
I didn't check my mirrors.
그냥 도와줘
아줌마 차에 태워줘
Just help-help me get her
in the car.
자, 일으킨다
간다, 일으켜!
Now come on. Sit her up.
Let's go. Sit her up.
문 열어, 문!
Get the door! Get the door!
(grunts)
됐어요?
Are we good?
그래, 됐어
가자!
Yeah, we're good. Go!
(tires squealing)
(tires squeal)
날이 왜 이 지랄이여?
What the hell?
지옥이 내려오네
Hell's down here.
같이 지옥행 타실래요?
You want a ride?
이 근처에 볼 일 있나?
You just happen
to be in the neighborhood?
비라도 좀 왔으면
좋겠네요
It'll be nice to get
a little bit of rain.
얘기 좀 하지
You and I need to talk.
누가 줄리아 셤웨이를 쐈네
Somebody shot Julia Shumway.
무시무시한 세상에
살고 있네요
It's a perilous
world we live in.
네가 쏜 거
알고 있어
I know it was you.
바비가 한마디 했을텐데요
내가 "No" 라는 말 싫어한다고
Well, Barbie said the one word
a girl hates to hear: "No".
어쩔셈이야, 맥스
Where is this going, Max?
당신한테 달렸어요, 지미
That's up to you, Jimmy.
인생은 언제나
옳은 선택에 달려있죠
Life's all about making
the right choices.
옳은 선택 하셨고,
잘 하셨어요
You make the right one,
you play nice,
우리한테는 잘 된거에요
and it's good between us.
당신도 바비처럼
빠지시려구요?
You step out of line
like Barbie did...?
혼자인게 더 좋지, 나는
Lucky for me I'm single.
오, 그럼 한사람 더
데려 와야 겠네요
Oh, I'm sure there's someone
around here you care about.
아빠
JUNIOR:
Dad.
가서 일 봐라,
주니어
Go on to work, Junior.
오, 드디어 만났네요
Well, look who
I finally get to meet.
- 주니어, 안녕?
- 안녕하세요
Junior, hi.
Hi.
네 아빠 친구란다
I'm a friend of your dad's.
안녕하세요
Hi.
와우, 너도 어쩔 수 없는
레니 집안 사람이구나
Wow, you are,
you're a Rennie, all right.
눈이...
Those eyes, it's, like...
it's like I'm looking
네 엄마를 쏙 빼 닮았구나
right at your mom.
경찰 하기에는 좀
I bet you face a lot of danger
안 어울리는
얼굴이라
being a police officer,
아버지가 걱정
많이 하시지?
and I bet your dad is just
constantly worried about you, huh?
됐어, 그만해
맥스
All right, that's enough, Max.
가봐야겠네요
I better get going.
버드 아일랜드에
일이 좀 있어서요
I have some business
to attend to on Bird Island.
날씨가 좀 안좋네
The weather's acting up.
배 타기에는 좀
위험할 거 같은데
I'm not sure it's a great
time to be on the water.
왠일로 걱정을
다 해주실까?
Aren't you sweet
to think about me?
네 아버지는 끝까지
친절하시구나
Your dad, he is so
thoughtful, to the end.
공장에 있을 테니까
도움이 필요하면
I'll be at the factory later on
찾아주세요
if you need me.
바이바이~
Ciao.
누구에요?
Who was that?
악마같은 년
The devil.
(horn blaring)
줄리아!
정신차려
Julia! Jul, hey, hey, hey,
stay with me.
야, 조! 서둘러!
정신잃고 있어!
Hey, you got to hurry, Joe.
She's crashing!
가고 있어요
I'm working on it.
(tires squeal)
죄송해요
Sorry.
잘한다, 조
빨리 빠져나가
You're doing great, Joe.
Just get us there.
하늘이 난리네요
It's pretty bad up there.
그래, 여기도
마찬가지거든, 조
Yeah, it's pretty bad
back here, too, Joe.
제 말은, 날씨가
나쁜게 아니라
I mean, it's not just
the weather.
돔이 이상한거 같아요
It's the dome.
우리한테
화가 난 거 같아요
I think it's angry at us.
(tires squeal)
줄리아, 다 왔어
I got Julia.
트렁크 열어서
차 충전시켜
You pop the trunk,
plug this thing in.
- 차 충전해놔야 돼
- 알겠어요
We need the juice.
Okay.
(wind whistling)
바비!
Barbie!
됐어, 안으로
옮기자
All right, let's get
her inside!
두번째 방에 눕혀요
Put her in the second room.
네, 그 방이요
Yeah, right there.
총알이 제거됐는지,
So, it's a through and through?
꼼꼼히 살펴봤어요?
Then there's no
bullet to remove?
네, 다 봤어요
That's right.
상처부위에
공기주입구를 뚫어서
Sounds like she's taking in air
through the wound,
압박하는걸
완화시켜줘야 돼요
so we've got to relieve
this pressure,
안그러면 심장이랑 폐가
짓눌릴거에요
or else it's gonna
crush her heart and lungs.
누가 좀 도와주세요
나무가 차고를 덮쳤어요!
Please, somebody,
a tree fell on our garage!
남편이 안에 있어요!
My husband was inside!
숨을 안쉬어요
He's not breathing!
(Julia wheezing)
가서 플라스틱 튜브
가져와
Go get me a piece
of plastic tubing
그걸로 흉부 압박을
좀 덜어줄 수 있을거야
so we can relieve the
pressure in her chest here.
아무것도 없어요
This place is picked clean.
펜이랑 플라스틱 백,
I'll make do with a pen,
plastic bag.
알콜 좀 집어와
Grab some alcohol.
펜, 플라스틱 백, 알콜...
Pen, plastic bag, the alcohol.
이런거는 어디서
배우셨어요?
How do you know
how to do all this?
팔루자에 있을 때
부대원한테 해 본 적이 있어
I had to chest tube
my team sergeant in Fallujah.
무슨 일이 있었는데요?
What happened to him?
(wind whooshing)
마을 사람들 총 전부
회수한거 아니었어요?
I thought everybody had
to turn in their guns.
난 안했다
I'm not everybody.
아빠, 무슨 일이에요?
Dad, what's going on?
아까 그 여자,
맥스...
That woman Max...
그 여자가 아빠가 해놓은
모든 걸 가져가서...
she's gonna take everything
I worked for...
파괴할 거다
and destroy it.
무슨 말이에요
What do you mean?
아들아, 아빠는
최선을 다했다
Son, I've been doing my damndest
마을을 정상으로
돌리기 위해서,
to get things back to normal,
순리에 맞게
돌아가도록 말야
make the trains run on time.
그런데 맥스가
마약이랑 술,
Max is trying
to fill those trains
건달들을
불러 모아서
with drugs and liquor
and every kind of sick vice
마을을 망치려
하고 있단다
human beings can get into.
그 여자 그렇게 안보이던데요
She seems nice enough to me.
그년은 그냥
Well, that just
네가 무슨 말을 하는지도
모르게 널 홀리는 거야
shows you don't know what
the hell you're talking about.
(wind whistling)
맥스는 화가 나 있다...
She's angry, Junior...
나한테
at me.
그래서 나한테
상처를 주려고 할거야
And she wants to hurt me...
널 미끼로 해서
by hurting you.
제가 도와드릴게요
Then let me help you.
내가 처리할 수 있다
I can handle this.
- 아빠, 돕게 해주세요
- 주니어, 안 된다
Dad, I can help.
Junior, no.
- 저도 남자에요, 할 수 있어요
- 주니어,
I'm a man. No, I can do something!
Junior.
주니어, 안 된다!
Junior, no!
홀아비로...
Single dad...
널 키웠다...
...raising a kid.
(inhales deeply)
내 인생에서 제일
잘 한 일이지
I did the best I could.
여전히 야단만 치시잖아요
But you still punish me for it.
그래, 안다...
I know I have,
하지만
더이상 안그러마
but not anymore.
아들아... 맥스같은
사람이랑은...
Look, son, with someone
like Max...
끝이 어떨지는
모르겠지만
...I don't know how this ends.
아빠, 그런 말씀은
하지 마세요
Dad, don't say that.
끝내야한다
It's the truth.
(wind whistling)
집에 있거라
You stay in the house.
나 말고는 절대
문 열어주지 말고
Do not open the door
for anybody but me.
알겠니?
Do you hear me?
(thunder crashes)
번개
Lightning.
무슨 일이 생기려는 걸거야
I wonder if that changes
anything.
좋아
Okay.
화상 전환
MAN (garbled):
Imagery transmission.
UHF 데이터 접속
UHF data adapter.
SATCOM
SATCOM.
맙소사
다시 작동하잖아
You're kidding me.
It's working again.
좋아, 컴온 베이비
All right, come on, baby.
(static)
똑바로 좀 말해봐라
Speak clearly.
입감
Affirm.
바비다, 확인완료
MAN 2:
It's Barbie. We've confirmed it.
바비?
Barbie?
알겠습니다
MAN 1:
Yes, sir.
방문자의 날 테잎으로
확인했다
We reviewed the tape
from visitors' day.
확실하다, 데일 바바라가
거기 있다
There's no question--
that's Dale Barbara in there.
롸져, 우리가 찾는 놈이다
MAN 2: Roger that. He's the
one we've been looking for.
(wind whistling)
(frantic knocking on door)
(knocking continues)
(screams)
여기서 뭐하고
자빠진거야?
What the hell are you doing?!
너야말로 여기서 뭐해?
I could ask you the same thing.
그냥 쏴라 이새끼야!
Well, don't bother shooting me!
마을 사람들
다 죽이시려고!
You're about to get
the whole town killed!
뭐?
What?
주니어, 밖이 어떤지
좀 봐!
Junior, look at what
it's doing!
저게 뭐야?
What is that?
메세지를 보내는거야
(droning sound)
It's sending a message.
다시 돌아와야 돼!
You have to come back
to the group.
넷이서 다같이 있지 않으면,
아무 의미 없어!
It takes all of us,
or we're nothing!
우리 얘기하는거야, 주니어
너말야!
It's talking to us, Junior.
To you!
뭐? 내가 날씨도 맘대로
할 수 있다고?
What, so now I control
the weather?
그동안 괴상한 일들이
많았지만
This thing has done
a lot of crazy stuff,
이런적은
한번도 없었어!
but never this.
네가 우릴 떠난다고 하기 전까지는
Not until you turned
your back on us.
(panting)
(monitor beeping)
바비?
Barbie?
전 괜찮아요
I'm okay.
(flatline tone sounds)
무슨 일이에요?
What's happening?
심박이 멈췄어
Her heart stopped.
압박이 너무 쎄
Too much pressure.
(grunts)
어우...
Uh...
(slurping)
뭐하시는거에요?
What are you doing?
줄리아 흉부에서
I'm sucking out
불필요한 공기
빼고 있어
the extra air in her chest.
빨리 와! 지하실로 가서
JUNIOR: Come on, we
gonna ride it out
- 일단 피해야 돼!
- 안돼! 너 미쳤어?
down in the shelter!
No, are you nuts?!
조하고 노리한테 가서
같이 있어야지!
We have to go be
with Joe and Norrie!
아빠가 어디가지 말고
여기 있으랬어!
My dad said to stay here.
주니어, 일 제대로
하고 싶어?
Junior, do you want
to make this right?
그럼 따라와!
Then come with me.
너한테 뭘 약속하고
그런게 아니라
Not because
I am promising you anything,
돔이 너한테
우리랑 같이
but because the dome
is telling you
있어야 한다고
했기 때문이야
what you're supposed to do
to be with us.
우린 네가 필요해!
We need you.
네가 날
필요로 한거야, 앤지
You need me, Angie.
좋아
Fine.
난 네가 필요해
I need you.
자 빨리 가자!
Now come on!
빨리와! 컴온!
Come on, we gotta come on!
앤지!
Angie!
봤어?
See?
내가 맞았어
I was right!
(flatline tone continues)
(wind howling)
(monitor beeping rhythmically)
됐어요!
It worked.
해내셨어요!
You did it.
네가 도와줬잖니
I had a little help, Joe.
폭풍이 그쳤네요
JOE:
Storm's breaking up.
가봐야 겠어요
I gotta go now.
사람들한테 말해야죠
I have to tell them.
누구한테 뭘 말해?
You have to tell who?
아저씨가 아줌마
구하셨잖아요
You saved Julia.
돔이 떨어진 날
절 구해주신 것처럼요
Just like you saved me
when the dome came down.
어쩌면 아저씨는 모두를
구해 주실지도 몰라요
Maybe you're here
to save all of us.
아닐꺼다
I don't think so, bud.
주니어 형 말이 맞아요
Junior was right.
The monarch는 사람이에요
The monarch's a person.
그 사람이 아저씨구요
That person's you.
(monitor beeping rhythmically)
한글자막 : 차이콥스키™ by DOTAL
영문자막 : honeybunny
출 처 : www.addic7ed.com
피드백 : moebius0537.tistory.com
맙소사,
엄마!
(sobs):
Oh, Mom.
(monitor beeping rhythmically)
저기, 제가
BARBIE:
Hey, listen.
자리를 비우고 싶지는 않지만,
가봐야 해서요
I don't want to leave her,
but I gotta go
그래서 그런데
좀 돌봐주실 수...
take care of something,
so could you...
아무데도 안가요
걱정마세요
She and I
aren't going anywhere.
고맙습니다
Thank you.
(vehicle approaching)
줄리아는 괜찮나?
Julia okay?
간신히요
Barely.
그건 그렇고
Still...
맥스가 쐈다는건
알고 있지?
you know it's Max
who shot her, right?
네
Yeah.
그리고 그 여자가 이젠
And I also know
그만 할 때라는 것도 알죠
that it's time to stop her.
우리 같이 할 일이
생겼구만 그래
It's take both of us to do it.
대신에 제 방식대로
따라주셔야 합니다, 짐
But we're gonna do this
by my rules, Jim.
맥스를 생포할거에요
We're taking Max alive.
오, 훌륭하구만
Oh, great.
그럼, 우리 거들먹
거리면서 가다가...
So we'll be high and mighty...
죽겠구만
and dead.
매사가 그런식이세요?
That's all you know, isn't it?
죽이지 않으면 죽는다?
Kill or be killed?
당신은 마을을 구한게
아니에요
You're not saving
Chester's Mill,
마을을 산채로
좀먹고 있던 거에요
you're eating this town alive.
- 넌 뭘 몰라 애송아
- 우린 이 일 하고,
You have no idea what it takes.
We do this,
그리고 나서
당신하고 나
and then you and I...
우린 끝이에요
we're finished.
지난 두 주 동안
저는,
I've spent the last two weeks
trying to convince myself
우리가 같은 걸
원한다고 생각했어요
that we want the same thing.
- 그랬잖나
- 아뇨
We do.
No.
전 더 나은 세상을 원해요
I want a future.
그런 세상에 더 가까워지길
원했다구요
I want something that
I can build towards.
당신은 왕국을 원했잖아요
You want a kingdom.
이 마을은 리더가 필요해
This town needs a leader.
당신 호의는 필요없어요
Not your kind.
착오가 좀 있었지만
Made a few mistakes.
난 누구보다
이 마을을 사랑하네
But nobody loves this town
better than I do.
아뇨, 당신은 권력을
탐한거에요, 짐
No, you love power, Jim.
그것 뿐이에요
That's it.
맥스를 잡은 후에는
볼 일 없는거에요
Now, we take down Max,
and we are done.
그리고 누가
뭐라던간에
And then I am gonna do
whatever I have to do
당신을 왕좌에서
끌어 내릴겁니다
to make sure that I knock
you off of your throne.
노리? 조는?
Norrie? Where's Joe?
모르겠는데요
I don't know.
줄리아 아줌마한테 갔다가
아직 안 왔어요
He went to go talk to Julia
and hasn't come back.
아, 그럼 아직 거기
있겠지, 그치?
Well, he must still
be there, right?
이 날씨에 다시 오려고는
안했을거야
He wouldn't try to come
back in this storm.
우리도 간신히 왔어
We barely made it ourselves.
네, 날씨 정말 이상해요
Yeah, that was so weird.
이런거 처음 봐요
It came out of nowhere.
그래, 이상해
Yeah, maybe not.
저 왔어요
Hey, guys.
조! 어디있다 온거야?
Joe! Where have you been?
- 줄리아 아줌마는?
- 총에 맞았어 / -뭐?
Where's Julia? What?
She got shot.
네, 가슴에...
Yeah, in the chest.
잠깐동안 숨이
멎었었는데,
And then she died for a minute,
괜찮아졌어
but she's gonna be okay.
바비 아저씨가
다시 살렸어
Barbie brought her back.
놀랬다니깐
It was incredible.
다행이다
Thank God.
있잖아...
Guys...
내 생각에는 아저씨가
그 왕인거 같아
I think he might be the monarch.
아저씨가
The tornado
아줌마 가슴에서 공기를
다 빨아내니까
went away right after
he finished sucking the air
- 폭풍이 멈췄다고, 그건...
- 으웩
out of her chest, it was...
Ew.
아니, 폭풍이 멈춘 건
그거 때문이 아냐
No, that's not why
the storm stopped.
뭐?
What?
내가 돌아오기로 결정해서
멈춘거라고
It stopped because
I decided to come back.
알겠어...
Okay...
봐봐, 뭔가 시작됐다가
Look, something started it,
뭔가가 멈췄어
and something stopped it.
그럼 우린 뭘 해야 할까?
But what do we do now?
돔으로 가야죠
(exhales)
We need to go to the dome.
(sighs)
밖에 큰 돔이요
The big dome.
맞아
Right.
이 별은 분명히 우리야
If these stars are really us,
별 위치랑 큰 돔에 찍힌 위치를
맞춰서 가야돼
then we have to go to
the same spot on the big dome.
북극성 아래에서...
Under the North Star...
정북으로...
due north...
정확히 볼링우드 다리
근처야
That's right around
the Bollingwood Bridge.
그리고 나서는?
And then what?
나도 몰라
I don't know.
동시에 만지면
뭔일이 생기겠지
Stuff happened when
we touched it together.
좋아
Okay.
우리 네 명이서
So... the four of us
정확히 동시에
뭘 해야하는거네
need to do the exact same thing.
의논은 그만하자
ANGIE:
Enough guessing.
(sighs)
돔은 뭔가 대답을 원하고 있어
The dome owes us some answers.
계획이 뭔가?
So what's the plan?
당당히 걸어들어가서
We march right in
맥스한테 잡혀줄건가?
and let her ambush us?
정문으로는
안 갈거에요
We're not going
in the front door.
폭격이 있던 날 줄리아가
다른 입구를 알려줬어요
Julia showed me another way
the day the missile hit.
뭐하나?
What are you doing?
이게 나갈 방법이에요
I'm giving us a way out.
그냥 알람시계에요
It's just an alarm clock.
씨발 알람시계로 뭘하려고?
The hell do we need
an alarm for?
(beeps)
만약을 대비하는거죠
(beeping rhythmically)
Just in case.
(rhythmic beeping continues)
가죠
Let's go.
줄리아 차는 없네요
PHIL:
Julia's car is gone.
바비가 데려간 거 같아요
I guess Barbie took her.
오, 세상에
Oh, God.
그리 멀리 간 거
같진 않아요
I didn't think he could
ever go this far.
바비를 어떻게 그렇게
잘 알지?
How well do you know Barbie?
아무나 그 사람을 알진 못해요
I don't think anybody knows him.
줄리아처럼
Julia does.
아니면 줄리아가
했던 것처럼
Or thought she did.
피터 셤웨이...
Peter Shumway...
그 사람, 수렁에 빠진거에요
he was in deep.
하우스에서 도박을 했어요
He bet the house.
말 그대로
Literally.
하우스요
The house.
그리고 돈을 잃었겠지
And lost.
바비는
수금원이었어요
And Barbie was
the collection agent.
뭐 그렇게
말랑한 사람은 아니죠
Wasn't too polite
about it, either.
진짜로 그렇게 생각...
Do you really think...
바비가 피터를 죽였다면...
If Barbie killed Peter...
그리고 줄리아가
알아챘구나
And then Julia found out.
뭐하는 건지
모르겠구만
I don't know about this.
입 좀 닥쳐주실래요?
Would you just shut your mouth
for once?
(gun hammer cocks)
안녕들 하신가?
Hello, boys.
계속 걸어
Keep walking.
이게 전부입니다, 보스
That's all they
were packing, boss.
짐이 내 엄마를 죽였어, 바비
Jim killed my mother, Barbie.
당신한테도
I don't suppose
얘기 안했을거 같았어,
그렇지?
he told you that, did he?
너네 둘 다 똑같은 것들이야
You two are just the same.
아닌데?
너랑 나라면 모를까...
I don't think so.
You and me, though...
뭐, 다른 얘기지만
well, that's a different story.
우리 참 좋았어 그렇지?
We were good together.
아니, 그런적 없었는데
No, we were never good.
네가 돈을 주고, 난 일을 하고
그게 다야
You paid me, I did a job,
that's it.
글쎄, 잘생긴 아저씨...
난 참 좋았는데...
Well, it's a good thing
you're handsome, brother,
가끔 정말로
둔해서 말이지
because you sure are
thick sometimes.
무슨 말이야?
What do you mean?
기회를 줬었다고...
(voice breaks): I mean, I'm
giving you a chance...
살 수 있는...
to live.
뭐, 너랑?
What, with you?
맥스, 넌 줄리아를 쐈어
Max, you shot Julia.
그녀는 너랑 절대
안 어울려
She was never right
for you, anyway.
나랑 안 어울리는 건
바로 너야, 맥스
You're the one
who's not right, Max.
널 위한 계획도 있었어
(voice catches):
I had plans for you.
난 널 믿었다고...
I trusted you...
그리고 네가 날 망쳤어
and you screwed me over.
너도 저인간이나
다른 마을 사람들이랑
You're no different from him...
다를게 없어
or from anyone else
in this town.
뭐야, 누가 누굴 얘길 하는거여?
Look who's talking.
아니, 아니지, 짐!
No, that is not true, Jim!
나는 너랑 달라!
I am nothing like you!
난 살아남았어!
I am a survivor!
다른 약속이
있으신가 본데
If you have plans
to be somewhere,
약속 잡으신 분은
매우 실망하시겠네
then someone is going
to be very disappointed.
(beeping rhythmically)
(beeping rapidly)
(clanking)
엎드려요!
BARBIE:
Get down!
(gasps)
자 이제,
전부 나간다
Now we are all leaving.
움직여!
Let's go. Go.
줄리아는 여기 있는데,
바비는 나갔데
Julia's here,
but Barbie's gone.
빅 짐이랑
같이 갔다던데
They said that he
took off with Big Jim.
분명히 시멘트 공장으로
갔을거에요
Could be at the cement factory.
맥스가 거기에
파이트 클럽을 차렸거든요
Max set up a fight club there.
돈 잃고 온 놈들 말이,
바비가 어제 거기 있었대요
Heard people say they lost
money on Barbie yesterday.
나와
Get out.
린다, 왜 이래요?
Come on. Linda,
이러면 안돼죠,
맨~
you cannot do this
by yourself, man.
네가 경찰할래, 필?
You're not a cop, Phil.
금방 갔다올게
I'll see you soon.
지금 내차 훔치는거죠?
You're stealing my car.
제가 우리 차
가져와서
I'll go get our car.
제가 서에다 저것들
집어 넣을게요
I'll take them
down to the station.
진짜 이러고 싶지는
않을텐데?
You don't want
to do this, I promise.
네가 잡은 약점은
이미 내가 가져갔어
I already took care of your
little insurance policy.
넌 짐작도 못할걸
(scoffs)
You have no idea.
끝났어
It's over.
무슨 짓을 하는거에요?
What the hell did you do?!
맥스는 살아 있는거
자체가
As long as Max is breathing,
위협적이야
she's a threat.
이젠 아니구만
Now she's not.
그리고 자네도
And neither are you.
(groans)
바비, 무기 버려요!
(gun cocks)
LINDA: Barbie, put that weapon down!
당장 버려요!
Put it down now!
린다!
신이시여 고맙습니다
BIG JIM:
Linda, thank God!
이 새끼 미쳤어!
He's gone nuts!
거짓말이에요!
He's lying to you!
이 새끼가 다 죽였어!
BIG JIM:
He killed 'em!
손을 묶고
머리에다가 땡겼다고
First he cuffed 'em, and then
he shot 'em in the head!
내가 다음 차례였어!
I was next!
물러서요, 바비
Back up, Barbie.
총 내려놔요
Put the weapon down.
손은 등 뒤로 돌리고
Put your hands
behind your back.
더 이상 희생자는 없겠구만
You killed your last victim.
다리 벌려요
Spread your legs apart.
자넨 끝이야
You're done.
린다, 제가 말하려고...
Linda, I'm telling you...
(Linda gasps)
멈춰요! 쏘기 전에!
Stop, or I'll shoot!
저 씨발새끼 빨리 쏴!
Shoot that son of a bitch!
(dry firing)
됐나?
BIG JIM:
Am I set?
2초만요
다 됐어요
Two secs.
Almost there.
- 짐?
- 왜?
Hey, Jim?
Yeah?
제가 오늘 뭘 좀 들었는데요
I heard something today.
밖에서 나는 소리요
From the outside.
바비에 관한 거에요
It was about Barbie.
무슨 말이야
What are you talking about?
군인들이었는데,
바비가 여기 있는걸 알더라구요
It was the military.
They know he's in here.
뭐라 그랬는지
정확하게 말해봐봐
Tell me exactly what they said.
바비가 그 중 한명이랬어요
They said that he's the one.
군인들이 찾고있는 한 사람
The one that they've been
looking for.
켜
Turn it on.
짐 레니입니다
This is Jim Rennie.
체스터스 밀에
매우 안좋은 소식을
I'm sorry to report
전해드려서
정말 유감입니다
that this has been a very dark
day in Chester's Mill.
주민 여러분 모두 조심하고
경계하셔야 합니다
I need all citizens
to be aware and vigilant.
오늘, 맥신 시그레이브와
동업자인 오토 아귈라가
Today, Maxine Seagrave
and her business associate
살해됐는데, 처형 당하듯
총에 맞았습니다
Otto Aguilar were murdered,
shot execution style.
많은 분들이 맥스를 아실겁니다
Many of you may have known Max.
그녀는 웨스트레이크에서
존경받는 사업가였습니다
She was a reputable
businesswoman from Westlake.
게다가, 줄리아 셤웨이 씨한테는
살해시도도 있었습니다
In addition, an attempt was made
on the life of Julia Shumway.
그녀는 가슴에
총상을 입었고
She suffered a gunshot
to the chest
생명이 위태롭습니다
and may not survive.
저역시 살해 위협을
받았습니다
There was also an attempt
made on my own life.
이 모든 일에 책임을 져야 할
단 한 사람은...
One person is responsible
for all this...
데일 "바비" 바바라 입니다
Dale "Barbie" Barbara.
그를 체포하기 위한 영장은
이미 발부됐습니다
A warrant has been issued
for his arrest.
그는 셤웨이 부인과
저에 대한
He's been charged
with the attempted murders
살해기도 혐의로
기소됐습니다
of Mrs. Shumway and myself.
그는 또한, 맥신 시그레이브,
오토 아귈라
He's also been charged
with the murders
그리고 시그레이브 씨의
어머니인
of Max Seagrave, Otto Aguilar,
아가사를 살해해
기소되었습니다
and Ms. Seagraves mother,
Agatha.
바비는 도주 중입니다
Barbie is on the run.
그는 무장을 해서
위험하기 때문에,
He is armed and dangerous,
제가 이렇게 긴급 성명을
발표하는 것입니다
and for those reasons, I'm
declaring a state of emergency.
이런 말도 안되는 범죄가
용인되서는 안됩니다
This senseless violence
will not be tolerated.
바비는 우리는
아랑곳하지 않을 겁니다
What Barbie did
is not who we are.
지금 이 순간에도,
언제라도 말이죠
Even now. Especially now.
바비가 구금되면
When Barbie is taken
into custody,
공정한 재판을
받을 것입니다
he'll be given a fair trial.
시 정부, 시민들
모두
The government,
그에게 죽음을 선고하길
바랄 것입니다
the people,
will seek the death penalty.
우리 넷이서
만졌을 때
ANGIE:
Any bets on what will happen
무슨 일이 생길지
내기할 사람 없어?
when the four of us touch it?
제가 원하는 건 해답이에요
All I want is answers.
발작이나 수수께끼가
아니라요
Not a seizure or riddle.
그냥 정답
Just answers.
좋아
All right,
무슨 일이 생기든
whatever happens,
도망가면 안돼
don't let go.
(soft zapping)
(zapping stops)
♪
아빠?
Dad?
아빠!
Dad!
주니어!
Junior.
안돼!
No!
아빠!
Dad!
아빠를 찾아야겠어
I gotta go find my dad.
기다려!
Wait!
우리 모두
같은 걸 본거야?
Did we all see the same thing?
빅 짐 아저씨?
Big Jim?
그래
Yeah.
도대체 뭐야?
What the hell was that?
여기 오면 답을
찾을 줄 알았는데
I-I thought we were coming here
for answers.
그래, 조
We were, Joe.
내 생각에는 이건 거 같아
I think that was it.
뭔데?
What was it?
돔이 무너져 내릴지도
모른다는 거
Maybe the dome's coming down.
우선...
First...
빅 짐 아저씨가 죽을거야
Big Jim has to die.
그리고 내 생각에는
우리가 아저씨를 죽여야 할거야
And I think
we're supposed to do it.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com